<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="/archive-stars2023/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/archive-stars2023/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2024-01-28T16:27:35-05:00</updated><id>/archive-stars2023/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Welcome to STaRS 2023 @ GGC!</title><subtitle>Georgia Gwinnett College yearly event Science Technology and Reseach Symposium (STaRS)</subtitle><author><name>STaRS IT subcommittee</name></author><entry><title type="html">2023 STaRS Poster Submission Instructions</title><link href="/archive-stars2023/stars2023/update/2023/02/23/poster-submission-instructions.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2023 STaRS Poster Submission Instructions" /><published>2023-02-23T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-02-23T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>/archive-stars2023/stars2023/update/2023/02/23/poster-submission-instructions</id><content type="html" xml:base="/archive-stars2023/stars2023/update/2023/02/23/poster-submission-instructions.html">&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Step1: Please register your poster &lt;a href=&quot;https://forms.gle/iHcEvjUf77Ki2guH7&quot;&gt; using this google form &lt;/a&gt; by March 3rd. 
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
Step2: Submit an electronic version(PDF) of the poster to &lt;a href=&quot;https://ggc.view.usg.edu/d2l/home/2559976&quot;&gt; this D2L site. &lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
Note: Poster dimensions should be 48” x 36”.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Important Deadlines: &lt;br /&gt;
Posters that will be printed by the SST office need to be in the D2L site by 3/31/2023 @ 5pm.  &lt;br /&gt;
Posters that will be printed by the faculty advisors still need to be electronically uploaded into the D2L site by 4/10/2023 @ 8am. &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>STaRS IT subcommittee</name></author><category term="stars2023" /><category term="update" /><summary type="html">Step1: Please register your poster using this google form by March 3rd.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Dean’s Message 2023</title><link href="/archive-stars2023/stars2023/update/2023/02/22/deans-message.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Dean’s Message 2023" /><published>2023-02-22T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-02-22T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>/archive-stars2023/stars2023/update/2023/02/22/deans-message</id><content type="html" xml:base="/archive-stars2023/stars2023/update/2023/02/22/deans-message.html">&lt;p&gt;Dear Colleagues, &lt;br /&gt;
As faculty and research scientists, we all recognize the importance of providing undergraduate research experiences for our students. The STaRS event is particularly important as it provides a venue for our students to showcase the outcomes of this high-impact practice - critical thinking, problem-solving, data analysis, oral communication, and community building to name a few. The Spring 2023 STaRS event will be many of our students’ very first opportunity to present the results of a significant amount of work to their professors and peers, in a supportive and celebratory environment. In addition, STaRS continues to represent our best opportunity to show campus leaders and colleagues in other departments the truly outstanding science that GGC students and faculty are doing every day. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year is especially important, as I’ve invited SST Corporate Affiliate Partners and Board of Visitor members to serve as guest judges for the poster presentations. They are excited to engage with our talented students!&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because of all of these factors, I am asking each and every faculty member who has conducted research with students to encourage your students to present their research at STaRS. We have plenty of space remaining to showcase your students’ work, and the STaRS Committee has extended the deadline for registration to March 3rd. I encourage all of you to take a few moments right now to go to the site for &lt;a href=&quot;https://forms.gle/iHcEvjUf77Ki2guH7&quot;&gt;registration for the Poster Showcase &lt;/a&gt;. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I experienced many notable highlights during my first year at GGC, I can confidently state that the Spring 2022 STaRS event was one of the most memorable. An excited crowd of students, faculty, staff, campus leaders, and industry partners converged in the H-building to support SST’s showcase of faculty-led undergraduate research. It was a spectacular day! With your participation, I know this year’s event will be just as, if not more, successful.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I look forward to seeing you all for an exciting afternoon of science on April 13th! &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Go Grizzlies! &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chavonda Mills &lt;br /&gt;
Dean, School of Science and Technology &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>STaRS IT subcommittee</name></author><category term="stars2023" /><category term="update" /><summary type="html">Dear Colleagues, As faculty and research scientists, we all recognize the importance of providing undergraduate research experiences for our students. The STaRS event is particularly important as it provides a venue for our students to showcase the outcomes of this high-impact practice - critical thinking, problem-solving, data analysis, oral communication, and community building to name a few. The Spring 2023 STaRS event will be many of our students’ very first opportunity to present the results of a significant amount of work to their professors and peers, in a supportive and celebratory environment. In addition, STaRS continues to represent our best opportunity to show campus leaders and colleagues in other departments the truly outstanding science that GGC students and faculty are doing every day.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Welcome to SST STaRS 2023!</title><link href="/archive-stars2023/stars2023/update/2023/02/03/welcome.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome to SST STaRS 2023!" /><published>2023-02-03T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-02-03T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>/archive-stars2023/stars2023/update/2023/02/03/welcome</id><content type="html" xml:base="/archive-stars2023/stars2023/update/2023/02/03/welcome.html">&lt;p&gt;Hello and Welcome to SST STaRS 2023!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/stars-2022.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>STaRS IT subcommittee</name></author><category term="stars2023" /><category term="update" /><summary type="html">Hello and Welcome to SST STaRS 2023!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Dean’s Message</title><link href="/archive-stars2023/stars2022/update/2022/03/18/deans-message.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Dean’s Message" /><published>2022-03-18T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2022-03-18T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>/archive-stars2023/stars2022/update/2022/03/18/deans-message</id><content type="html" xml:base="/archive-stars2023/stars2022/update/2022/03/18/deans-message.html">&lt;p&gt;Dear Colleagues,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since arriving at GGC, I have heard so much about the tradition of the School of Science and Technology’s annual, signature celebration of scholarship in the sciences:  STaRS.  I have seen photographs from past events, and I am excited to participate in my very first STaRS on April 14th.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you all are aware, undergraduate participation in faculty-led research is one of the highest of high impact practices for students interested in pursuing a career in the sciences.  An important part of this experience is the presentation of the results of the student’s research in a professional setting.  One of the important components of STaRS is the students’ presentation of research posters.  This will be many of our students’ very first opportunity to present the results of a significant amount of work to their teachers and peers, in a supportive and celebratory environment.  In addition, this represents our best opportunity to show campus leaders and colleagues in other disciplines the truly outstanding science that GGC students and faculty are doing every day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year is especially important, as this event will be the first live STaRS event that we will have held since the beginning of the COVID outbreak.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because of all of these factors, I am asking each and every faculty member who has conducted research with students in the last few years to coax and cajole your students to present their research at STaRS.  We have plenty of space remaining to showcase your students’ work, and the STaRS Committee has extended the deadline for registration to April 1st, and I encourage all of you to take a few moments right now to go to the site for &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/forms/d/1oUs-BtFuehzKeAHgObwVR8Y7j-2PYg9RtW9KiUjt3lg/edit?ts=620d5e44&quot;&gt;registration for the Poster Showcase&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I look forward to seeing you all for an exciting afternoon of science on April 14th!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Go Grizzlies!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chavonda Mills&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dean,
School of Science and Technology&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>STaRS IT subcommittee</name></author><category term="stars2022" /><category term="update" /><summary type="html">Dear Colleagues,</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">STaRS Poster Submission Instructions</title><link href="/archive-stars2023/stars2022/update/2022/03/01/poster-submission-instructions.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="STaRS Poster Submission Instructions" /><published>2022-03-01T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2022-03-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>/archive-stars2023/stars2022/update/2022/03/01/poster-submission-instructions</id><content type="html" xml:base="/archive-stars2023/stars2022/update/2022/03/01/poster-submission-instructions.html">&lt;p&gt;Poster presentations should be first registered through the online form (see email!).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you are ready to submit your actual poster, follow these guidelines:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Submit as PDF file&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Upload to &lt;a href=&quot;https://ggc.view.usg.edu/d2l/lms/dropbox/user/folder_submit_files.d2l?db=2030709&amp;amp;grpid=0&amp;amp;isprv=&amp;amp;bp=0&amp;amp;ou=2246996&quot;&gt;D2L dropbox&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Optionally, upload a video recording in MP4 format of the poster presentation to the same dropbox&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Video should be shorter than 10 minutes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>STaRS IT subcommittee</name></author><category term="stars2022" /><category term="update" /><summary type="html">Poster presentations should be first registered through the online form (see email!).</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Welcome to STaRS 2022!</title><link href="/archive-stars2023/stars2022/update/2022/02/03/welcome.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome to STaRS 2022!" /><published>2022-02-03T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2022-02-03T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>/archive-stars2023/stars2022/update/2022/02/03/welcome</id><content type="html" xml:base="/archive-stars2023/stars2022/update/2022/02/03/welcome.html">&lt;p&gt;Hello and Welcome to STaRS 2022!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/stars-2022.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Organizers&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>STaRS IT subcommittee</name></author><category term="stars2022" /><category term="update" /><summary type="html">Hello and Welcome to STaRS 2022!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Thank you for a successful STaRS!!!</title><link href="/archive-stars2023/stars2021/update/2021/04/17/thank-you.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Thank you for a successful STaRS!!!" /><published>2021-04-17T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2021-04-17T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>/archive-stars2023/stars2021/update/2021/04/17/thank-you</id><content type="html" xml:base="/archive-stars2023/stars2021/update/2021/04/17/thank-you.html">&lt;p&gt;Thank you for volunteering for and participating at the STaRS event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please check our posters page for the judging results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A special thank you to all the judges who worked during the meeting:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hoping to see you next year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Organizers&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>STaRS IT subcommittee</name></author><category term="stars2021" /><category term="update" /><summary type="html">Thank you for volunteering for and participating at the STaRS event.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Welcome to STaRS</title><link href="/archive-stars2023/stars2021/update/2021/04/08/welcome-to-stars.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome to STaRS" /><published>2021-04-08T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2021-04-08T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>/archive-stars2023/stars2021/update/2021/04/08/welcome-to-stars</id><content type="html" xml:base="/archive-stars2023/stars2021/update/2021/04/08/welcome-to-stars.html">&lt;p&gt;Welcome everyone,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Find the event you want to visit and click on the &lt;em&gt;Live Video link&lt;/em&gt; to
join the session. Enter the password provided in your email.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have issues, come to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://ggc-edu.zoom.us/j/94859760946&quot;&gt;lobby Zoom meeting&lt;/a&gt; to ask
for help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Organizers&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>STaRS IT subcommittee</name></author><category term="stars2021" /><category term="update" /><summary type="html">Welcome everyone,</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Dean’s Message</title><link href="/archive-stars2023/stars2021/update/2021/04/02/deans-message.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Dean’s Message" /><published>2021-04-02T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2021-04-02T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>/archive-stars2023/stars2021/update/2021/04/02/deans-message</id><content type="html" xml:base="/archive-stars2023/stars2021/update/2021/04/02/deans-message.html">&lt;p&gt;Dear GGC family,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As many of you may know, each year, the School of Science and Technology (SST) hosts its annual Science, Technology and Research Showcase (STaRS) in April. While the pandemic prevented us from hosting STaRS in April 2020, I am happy to announce that we are making a comeback in April 2021! Yes, our annual showcase of student research will be online this year on &lt;strong&gt;Thursday, April 8th from 12-3 pm.&lt;/strong&gt; You will receive more details in an email from our STaRS committee that has worked tirelessly in collaboration with staff from across the campus to bring this event back in a new format.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On behalf of SST and the STaRS committee, I invite you to join us online for STaRS. Meet with graduate and professional school representatives, gain new knowledge, and support your peers, students and friends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I look forward to seeing you all online.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sincerely, &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Sonal Dekhane&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
Interim Dean, School of Science and Technology&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>STaRS IT subcommittee</name></author><category term="stars2021" /><category term="update" /><summary type="html">Dear GGC family, As many of you may know, each year, the School of Science and Technology (SST) hosts its annual Science, Technology and Research Showcase (STaRS) in April. While the pandemic prevented us from hosting STaRS in April 2020, I am happy to announce that we are making a comeback in April 2021! Yes, our annual showcase of student research will be online this year on Thursday, April 8th from 12-3 pm. You will receive more details in an email from our STaRS committee that has worked tirelessly in collaboration with staff from across the campus to bring this event back in a new format.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">STaRS Poster Rubrics Feedback</title><link href="/archive-stars2023/stars2021/update/2021/03/09/rubrics-feedback-posters.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="STaRS Poster Rubrics Feedback" /><published>2021-03-09T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2021-03-09T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>/archive-stars2023/stars2021/update/2021/03/09/rubrics-feedback-posters</id><content type="html" xml:base="/archive-stars2023/stars2021/update/2021/03/09/rubrics-feedback-posters.html">&lt;p&gt;Poster Rubrics Feedback:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Video only posters get 1 pt deduction from final score&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Presentation Scoring&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Criteria&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;5&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Reseach Topic or Problem is relevant to SST STEM domains.&lt;br /&gt; Design and methodology is sound.&lt;br /&gt;Creativity is evident with sound execution.&lt;br /&gt;Excellent presentation.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;4&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Reseach Topic or Problem is relevant to SST STEM domains.&lt;br /&gt; Design and methodology is acceptable. &lt;br /&gt; Sound execution is demonstrated. &lt;br /&gt; Very good presentation.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;3&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Reseach Topic or Problem is relevant to SST STEM domains.&lt;br /&gt; Design and methodology is demonstrated.&lt;br /&gt; Average execution is demonstrated.&lt;br /&gt;Sound presetation.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;2&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Reseach Topic or Problem  may or may not pertain to SST STEM domains. &lt;br /&gt;Design and methodology is demonstrated. &lt;br /&gt; Below average execution is demonstrate. &lt;br /&gt; Acceptable presentation&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Reseach Topic or Problem does not pertain to SST STEM domains.&lt;br /&gt; Limited design or execution &lt;br /&gt; Poor presentation&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;</content><author><name>STaRS IT subcommittee</name></author><category term="stars2021" /><category term="update" /><summary type="html">Poster Rubrics Feedback:</summary></entry></feed>